Yulu CHENG

Hong Kong • +852 55342311 • yoela.yl.cheng@gmail.com

PERSONAL SUMMARY

Seeking an opportunity as a business/data analyst as career transformation. With over 3 years of experience in Internet advertising and marketing industry, I have gained extensive knowledge in e-commerce and enhanced my skills in effective communication with multiple stakeholders. Pursuing a Master's degree in the AI and digital media program at HKBU, I have acquired fundamental skills in data processing and analysis and eager to apply these skills in a practical workplace.

EDUCATION

HONG KONG BAPTIST UNIVERSITY

Hong Kong

Master of Science (MSc) in AI and Digital Media

Sept. 2023 - Present

Course: Big Data Management and Analytic, Data Mining and KDD, Basic Programming for Data Science, Data Visualization

GPA: 4.0/4.0 (1st Semester)

SHANTOU UNIVERSITY

Bachelor of Arts (MA) in Advertising
GPA: 3.56/5.0 (Average 85+)

Shantou, China Sept. 2014 - Jun. 2018

PROJECTS

Automated Content Management System - *Movie Recommendation and News Generation*Project Presentation Link

SQL, Python

This project aims to provide a user-friendly system for movie searching and news generation based on individual input, such as movie names and genres. These templates cover a wide range of queries, enabling users to access comprehensive information about movies, actors, genres, and industry trends.

Key implementation process:

- Cleaned and split the original JSON datasets using Python to ensure accurate and consistent data.
- Designed relations and schemas for each table, creating a relational database with SQLite.
- Established database connection and fully managed it using Python code, including insertion, update, deletion, and querying.
- Wrote SQL queries (utilizing subqueries and aggregate functions) and developed Python code to enable searching, news generation, and textual user interfaces.
- Utilized Python libraries such as matplotlib.pyplot, seaborn, and WordCloud to realize data visualization.

WORK EXPERIENCE

ByteDance | Business Center - SVIP Service Department Sales Operation Specialist

2020.08 - 2021.01

KPI & Process Management:

- Formulated and tracked monthly/annual sales team KPIs, ensuring alignment with objectives.
- Analyzed and reported sales data on a regular basis (weekly/monthly/bi-monthly).
- Sort out the internal and external policies, resolving basic business issues like contract management and client conflicts.
- Collaborated with other departments (product, planning, industry operation) to establish and maintain business connections. Sales Support:
- Conducted financial analysis for key clients (P&G/Estee Lauder/L'Oreal) regularly.
- Performed market research on competitor apps to gather budget data for key clients.
- Analyzed media data and curated high-quality TikTok case studies in FMCG industry.

Kugou Music | Media Assets Regulatory Department Advertising Executive Specialist

2019.04 - 2020.07

Kugou is a digital music interactive application and leading enterprise in mainland China, which committed to providing perfect solutions for Internet users and developing the Chinese digital music industry.

Sales Support:

- Coordinated with the sales team to ensure timely delivery of advertising schedules and plans for customers.
- Standardized Ad materials review SOP based on product documentation and advertising regulations for the sales team.
- Implemented the scheduled ad plan and generated data as required, analyzing reasons for exposure and click fluctuations.

Ad Product Operation:

- Operated and tracked the launch of new ad products, including Programmatic Ad, GDT Ad, and One-Minute-Task Ad;
 Collaborated with ad product engineers to implement Canary Testing and developed three external revised product introductory documentation for the sales team.
- Conducted regular ad inspections on Apps and websites, reporting any abnormal bugs to ad-product engineers for resolution.
- Integrated internal feedbacks for advertising operation systems and assisted engineers in implementing system optimization.

SKILLS & INTERESTS

Technical: SQL, Python (Numpy, Pandas), Tableau, Bloomberg Terminal

Language: English, Mandarin (Native), Cantonese (Basic)